Egor Philippov

E: philippovegor@gmail.com
W: www.egorphilippov.me
G: github.com/hoboman313



About Me

I am a dedicated and passionate full stack software engineer specializing in building modern SaaS web applications. My current go-to tech stack is **Ember.js** + **Bootstrap** + **Sass** for the frontend, **Node.js** for the middle tier, **NoSQL** (DynamoDB, MongoDB) for the backend and deployed via **AWS** (cloudfront, elastic beanstalk, elasticache - redis, etc...). I am actively operating and developing numerous web applications including: https://www.tomati.io/ and http://www.huegasm.com/ (also available as a Chrome extension and Android app).

Work Experience

Fullstack Web Developer at Google: Nest Labs (via Appnovation)

Remote & Palo Alto — Oct. 2016 - Present

Development of a web application (https://enterprise.nest.com/) for Nest enterprise partners written with an Ember.js SPA and a Golang RESTful API backend.

Languages/Tools: Ember.js, Golang, MySQL, Nginx, Redis, Docker, TeamCity, Git

Accomplishments

- Full stack development utilizing an Ember.js SPA + Golang API
- Configuration and management of builds through TeamCity
- Dockerizing the web application for GCP deployment
- Analysis and optimization for a production environment (mozilla observatory stuff like proper CSP and cache headers, SRI, optimal cookie pathing, etc...)

Senior Software Engineer, Absolute Software Co.

Vancouver, BC — Jan. 2014 - Oct.2016

Development of various enterprise web applications for remote management of devices written with an Ember.js SPA frontend and a Java RESTful API backend.

Languages/Tools: Ember.js, Java EE (Jersey + Spring), SQLite, MongoDB, Bash scripting, Node scripting, TeamCity, Git, TFS, (a little) C++

Accomplishments

- Full stack development utilizing an Ember.js SPA + Java API for numerous b2b products
- Implementation of push notifications for automatic data updates using WebSocket push notifications via the Atmosphere framework
- Creation and deployment of builds through TeamCity
- Management and configuration of a linux-based dev environment
- Analysis and optimization of a production environment for a SaaS product

Intermediate Software Engineer, OpenBet Technologies Ltd.

Burnaby, BC — Aug. 2012 - Jan. 2014

Development for playnow.com, technical analysis of customer requirements.

Languages/Tools: TCL, JavaScript (Backbone.js, RequireJS), Informix, Bash scripting, Linux command line

Accomplishments

- Development to allow for operators to manually register players through the back office system
- Worked on the technological analysis for upcoming projects
- Ported the existing backend generated HTML templates to be compiled and rendered using Handlebars
- Developed an architecture for 3rd party vendors to be allowed restricted access to the back office system

Intern Developer, SAP

Vancouver, BC — Aug. 2009 - Aug. 2010

Bug fixing, troubleshooting, enhancements, new development of the installation software for various company products

Languages/Tools: Java, Perforce, Visual Studio 2005, Eclipse

Accomplishments

- Developed and maintained a system for uploading the installed product information to a web server
- Collaboratively worked on an installer for an upcoming new product (SAP Business Objects Explorer) with a team from France
- Troubleshot problems pertaining to general installation features
- Improved and maintained existing product installer functionality

Other Experience & Projects

- A web application for searching the restaurant health inspection reports: https://www.tomati.io (currently in active development)
- A web application for controlling Philips Hue lights and synchronizing the beat of the user's music with them: http://www.huegasm.com
- Co-taught introductory web development to high school students through BrainStation Vancouver
- Used to develop plugins for a popular game called Counter Strike 1.6. My old, publicly available plugins are still up at: http://www.amxmodx.org/compiler.php?mod=1&cat=0&plugin=&author=hoboman&go=search

Education

Simon Fraser University

Bachelor of Science in Computing Science — 2009-2012